MANISH SONAL

Sr. Perl/ Bash Developer | DevOps Engineer

Nationality:IndianAddress:Pune, IndiaPhone number:+91-8149064050

Email address: manish.techrel@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/manish-sonal/

Professional Summary

Solution-focused Software professional with several years of experience developing and maintaining large-scale, robust distributed systems. Instrumental in designing CI/CD pipelines, managing DevOps processes, design new automation and deployment utilities/tools, ensuring data security and protection, implementation and maintenance of Identity and Access Management, privilege access management, and providing level-3 administrative support.

Work Experience

TATA Consultancy Services • Pune • India Sr. Perl/ Python Developer | DevOps Engineer

06/2018 - present

Client: Morgan Stanley & Co. LLC

- Experience in designing, developing, troubleshooting, and maintaining mission-critical analytics and application.
- Hands-on Experience on Perl/ Python/ Bash programming and OOP implementation.
- · Well-versed with Agile and DevOps methodologies.
- Designed and Implemented different automation and deployment utilities using Perl, Python, Bash technologies.
- Experienced working in REST api and REST client.
- Outstanding writing/analysing performance of complex SQL queries.
- Developing CI/CD roadmap and implementing the DevOps processes.
- Play a significant role in establishing operational processes for a fast-growing distributed cloud platform.
- Implemented continuous integration pipelines using Jenkins to automatically build and test code changes.
- Automated the provisioning and deployment of application infrastructure using Ansible and Terraform.
- Using **Docker** for containerization and **Kubernetes** for container orchestration.
- Experience working with different VCS including Bitbucket/Git, Perforce, and GitHub.
- Configured monitoring and logging tools such as Nagios to provide visibility into system performance and activity.
- Improve deployment process within **Azure** and on-prem.
- Monitor, analyse, and report performance statistics for cloud-hosted environments.
- Consult and contribute to system architecture.
- Write clean, well-documented, and resilient code.
- Outstanding problem solving, self-motivated and guick learner.

TATA Consultancy Services • Pune • India Cyber Security Integrator

03/2015 - 06/2018

Client: Morgan Stanley & Co. LLC

- Worked in Information Security and Risk division and supported different areas of Identity and Access Management.
- Managed different areas of Identity and Access Management Privileged access management, entitlements reviews, RBAC implementation for critical infrastructure components, and applications deemed highly restricted/confidential.
- Designed and developed automated deployment and scaling processes based on a wide range of server types and application tiers.
- Interact with Product/ Application owners and identify onboard/ off-board gaps impacting
 privileged access management, formulated recommendations for implementing the desired
 level of access controls across multiple platforms, which ensured the successful
 implementation of action plans.
- Review and design process for Azure PIM role access request process and manage it.
- Generate reports for quarter/annual security reviews of key financial applications and track and monitor activities and identify security vulnerabilities.
- Research the latest information technology (IT) security trends and develop security standards and best practices for organizations.
- Design Service-Now forms Develop complex workflows and scripts as per requirements to support the ITSM process.
- Led a team of five to develop an information security program for a large organization.
- Defined the organization's information security policies and procedures.
- Implemented an information security program that included security awareness training and incident response procedures.
- Monitored the organization's information security posture and reported on findings to.

SunGard Wall Street Concepts USA (http://www.wsc.com) • Pune • India Product Development Engineer- BackEnd

12/2013 - 03/2015

- Re-factor/Rewrite the classic ETL application framework into Perl using OOPS concepts.
- Meeting with Product Owners to Interpret the requests and discuss solutions and implement them within the application.
- Analyse and pin-point the bugs in the application and fix them.
- Participate in application architectural design decisions.
- Support the Operation team in fixing production bugs and issues.
- Perform Unit tests, UAT, and SIT testing for the code changes.
- Defined project requirements and objectives and created project plans to meet deadlines
- Coordinated with cross-functional teams to ensure all project deliverables were met

IBM India Pvt. Ltd. • Pune • India Role: **Application Programmer**

08/2010 - 12/2013

- Sustain the application by timely resolution of issues and ensuring application availability.
- Process work requests by monitoring and maintaining work gueues.
- Collaborate with client to understand their needs to implement end-to-end solutions by writing new scripts, code, and configuration changes.
- Identify and implement preventive maintenance recommendations to make the application more stable.
- Participating in SILO audits and baseline audits.
- Complete analysis of the application and design documents under the Plan and Define phase of the Synergy project.

Skills:

Platforms and Systems:

- Linux / Unix OS / Linux CLI
- Windows OS
- Public Cloud (Azure, AWS)

Programming/Scripting languages:

- Perl
- Python
- Bash
- Javascript

Databases:

- Sybase DB
- MySQL DB/ MariaDB
- MongoDB

Software Products and Platforms:

- VCS: BitBucket/Git, GitHub, Perforce, SVN, IBM Rational ClearCase
- Automation Platform: **Ansible, Terraform**
- CI Server: Jenkins
- Monitoring: Nagios, Prometheus, Grafana
- Containerization: Docker
- Container Orchestration: Kubernetes
- Cloud DevOps: Azure DevOps, AWS
- Project Management: **JIRA Confluence**
- IDE experience: VIM, Pycharm, Juypter Notebooks, VSCode
- ITSM: ServiceNow

Education:

Government Engineer College, Ajmer, India 2005 – 2009

• Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

Certifications and Trainings:

AZ-500: Azure Security Engineer Associate

Microsoft

03/2022 https://www.credly.com/badges/e9509fdb-9ce9-4ef2-8568-051fc13ad3fa?

source=linked in profile

AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator Associate

Microsoft

04/2022 https://www.credly.com/badges/7f80ccce-464d-4734-84c2-c0d171bb5891?

source=linked in profile

Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) Certification

Edureka

03/2022 https://www.edureka.co/certificates/mycertificate/

edbe666519d7d3252b629ec2fc8b5586

DevOps Engineer

Edureka

05/2022 https://www.edureka.co/my-certificate/f88b1fe2c85ec7e0671dac7de68a0bfb